ALLIA BOURNE MBA.FCCA/CPA.ACMA.CGMA

in www.linkedin.com/in/alliabourne

1125 Old Graves Mill Road Lynchburg - Virginia 24502 | C: 786 218 3615 | allia.bourne@yahoo.com

Executive Profile

Highly accomplished, results-driven executive with **Multi-industry and Global Experience** strengthening and leading corporate finance function. Commercially savvy Business Partner with **+20 years' experience** with background in small **Private** company & Large **Public Listed companies** with up to **\$25 billion** in revenue.

Industry Experience

Industrial Manufacturing, Service Contracts, Telecommunications, IT/Ecommerce, SAAS & Department of Defense Contracting. (CPG) Consumer Packaged Goods, Distribution & Retail and Supply company

Core Competencies

Strategic Planning (AOP) | Business Performance Management | Budget Process | Growth Strategy Development | Financial Analysis & Reporting | Global Outsourcing Efficiencies | Business Expansion & Start up's | Sox Controls & Audit Planning | Commercial Business Partnering | Financial Reporting | Developing Successful Multi-Cultural Team | SSC set up

Professional Experience

Dover Corporation - Public (NYSE) DOV



(Dover Corporation - Publicly Listed is a diversified Global manufacturer that delivers innovative equipment components, specialty systems, consumable supplies, software and digital solutions and support services. Operates is over 100 countries Globally.

CFO – (Belvac Operating Company)

Virginia 11/2019 – Present

Executive Business Partner reporting directly to President. Leading - Finance, Procurement, IT & Strategic Planning & M&A.

- Lead and closed major Acquisition, Implemented ERP and reorganize the corporate structure +\$500M
- Revaluated value chain of bid contracts of +\$300M in Service contracts major Blue-chip companies + 8% in Margin Uplift.
- Restructured and created a NA Finance team that is commercially focused, detailed great Business Partners for all functions.
- Implement Supply Chain Financing with JP Morgan and Automated billing platform will generate +\$100M in savings.
- Lead closed 2 successful major acquisitions. EPP implementation/synergies/Integration/strategy realignment.

_×Di-li

DHI Telecom Group - (Private Company)

Texas 01/2018 - 11/2019

(DHI Telecom Group privately held, is a USA. Department of Defense (DoD) telecommunications provider)

CFSO - Chief Financial & Strategy Officer

Key Business Partner reporting directly to Group CEO & Board of Directors. Lead Finance, Strategy and M&A across group.

- Recruited in for my extensive background in Global Multinational CPG group to grow and Scale a +\$300m business –
 Results 4 acquisitions completed in 18 months. ERP system implemented, 130% Organic and Non-Organic growth. IPO
 pending in 12 months current business +\$650m.
- Identified, Lead, Financed & closed 4 acquisitions totaling +\$280m leading synergies of over \$20m to EBITDA
- Recruited talent and scale the function for growth and IPO readiness Established budgetary systems, Reporting process and Key Matrices to Board and CEO,
- Partnered with DOD to establish best in class contracting KPI. 20% reduction in OPEX/CAPEX spend
- Treasury and cash optimization +\$50m Liquidity generated through rationalized of global fleet, contracting vs full time headcount, and divesting non-core assets to focus on key strategic pillars.
- Performance management system implemented, and credit control streamlined and outsourced for efficiency

Cable & Wireless Communications - Public (NASDQ-LILAK)



03/2012 - 01/2018

(Cable & Wireless Communications Ltd publicly listed, is Leading Multinational Telecommunications company - subsidiary of Liberty Global)

Regional Vice President Finance (B2B)

Florida 06/2015 - 01/2018

Promoted in recent merger to provide fiscal leadership of B2B business, reporting, treasury, risk management, and central functions. Challenged to reduce expenses and build a consolidated cohesive team across the region.

• Led effort in attracting and developing finance talent in support of \$4business. Consolidated finance activities in reporting and corporate accounting, and effectively streamlining merged units reducing headcount by 20.

- Reviewed finance organization established new organizational structure recruited new CFO for business regions.
- Key leader of Operation Excellence that eliminated \$60m of SG&A costs through further organizational restructuring and cost reductions.
- Championed the development and implementation of a Balanced Scorecard business performance reporting tool to evaluate monthly results against key success measures.

VP Finance – FP&A & Operations (Corporate)

Florida 10/2013 to 06/2015

- Prepare Annual Budgets Lead on Long Range Planning and AOP target setting and Rolling forecasts for Commercial BU and E Commerce & Digital in all markets
- Set ROI targets for all Retail stores ensuring optimum sales collections targets are met
- Manage the operations of the P2P Accounts Payable processing of vendor invoices, vendor returns, check runs etc.
- Manage large diverse team of collections agents internal and external of 40 and ramps to 60 during peaks.
- \$80m + liquidity generated through strategic company and due diligence process Provides leadership in the development for the continuous evaluation of short and long-term strategic financial objectives.
- \$2m interest cost savings through multi country cash pooling system and treasury standardization.
- 15% reduction in procurement spends through regional strategy deals with suppliers & partners.

CFO - Consumer Market Division (B2C)

Florida 03/2012 to 10/2013

- Delivered \$5M in cost/revenue efficiencies, mitigating inflationary pressures FX losses to allow for EBITDA and gross margin expansion.
- Accountable for on budget and on time \$40M footprint restructuring and capital investment program.
- Exceeded 10% reduction in workforce by leading significant organizational restructuring.
- Responsible for \$85m cost base, ~\$900m B Sheet, leading a finance, commercial sales and procurement team of 75.
- Accountable for annual planning, business performance, commercial business partnering, accounting, controls and compliance including external auditor reviews and financial filings.
- Implement procurement strategy delivering 20% savings to group on OPEX and CAPEX.

DIAGEO PLC - Public (NYSE - DEO)



(Florida & Other locations) 08/2007 – 01/2012

(Diageo plc is a publicly listed Multinational Alcoholic beverages company, with offices in 180 countries Globally and all Six continents. Diageo is the World's Largest Manufacturing & Distribution company of Premium Beverages)

Director of Finance - Compliance & Ethics

Florida 12/2010 - 01/2012

- Lead corporate governance, financial regulation, and control & compliance (SOX 404) compliance across all markets.
 Lead all operational internal and external audit process. Advise CEO & Board on compliance
- Improved the level of corporate governance and SEC, GAAP & FAC reporting requirements in markets by doing on site reviews, facilitating deep dives, and sharing of learning's and best practice and ensuring that all markets remain on a curve of continuous improvement.
- Prepare annual audit working paper, including all documents required by the auditors internal/external
- Provide reporting information for Audit Committee and Risk Management Committees
- Manage AR, AP, RTR and Chart of Accounts Regional project implementation. ERP SAP

Director Finance (Global Supply)

Florida 02/2009 to 12/2010

- Build/lead annual Budgets of US\$900m and variance analysis GAP closing commercial initiatives. Business
 partner for CEO in a US\$900m business. Manage Finance on all aspects of supply chain for segment
- Lead consolidation, reporting of regional SCM & CGS budget, actual, Forecast and variance analysis
- Builds great business partnering relationships with Commercial Sales VP, Marketing SVP, and support CFO in leading
 a cross-functional planning, pricing and review process. Lead analysis of Capital Plan US\$400m using NPV, IRR,
 DCF, OROA and EVA
- P&L EBIT balance sheet and cashflow management and strategic planning of 20 countries

Director Financial Planning Analysis

Florida 08/2007 to 01/2009

- Manages the AOP strategic planning, budgeting, and goal setting processes that establish and communicate business targets. Budget setting and monitoring of Capital and G&A budgets
- Sets Functional/department goals and objectives and manages to these through R&O.
- Lead and manage and implement process standardization in 30 markets with resulting successful audit of the CAFEC markets. Own P&L and Balance sheet total for region.
- Implement credit management credit policies and inventory management in plants/markets and trade terms in markets, resulted in 90% reduction in overdue and 20% reduced working capital
- Manage multicultural finance team which won multiple awards.

Red Stripe - Public (Listed symbol DG) Red Stripe is a publish the stripe is a publish the stripe.



Multiple Locations 01/2000 - 07/2007

(Red Stripe is a publicly listed Worldwide Iconic Beer Company and a Subsidiary of DIAGEO PLC - Red Stripe Beer is manufactured distributed and sold Globally.)

Group Financial Controller

09/2006 - 07/2007

- Lead all aspects of the financial controls team from finance to tax and treasury.
- Perform the duties of Secretary to the Board, Lead all board meeting financial preparation
- Manage external reporting to local stock exchange. Manage SOX testing and reporting
- Manage relationships with board and minority shareholders external audit process.

Finance Plant Controller – 5 Plants

02/2004 to 08/2006

- Manage the annual Strategic Financial Planning process manage all local targets and being lead finance contact on monthly Supply BPM review and Strat plan/AOP management.
- Lead role as Finance process owner for the implementation of SAP4.7 ERP
- Maintains cost accounting system for plant, analytical reviews ROI/NPV/IRR for capital projects

Finance Commercial Manager

01/2000 to 01/2004

- Received three business performance awards for outstanding financial management. & target delivery.
- Manage all Capital Investment appraisals and recommend projects to board that adds value to Red Stripe based on a wide range of financial and operating criteria.

Education

- Master of Business Administration MBA, University of Oxford Brookes Oxford UK, 2005
- Association of Chartered Certified Accountant ACCA/CPA 2001
- Chartered Institute of Management Accountant/Certified Public Accountants CIMA 2003

Additional Coursework and Professional Development & Software experience

- IFRS/US GAAP Training, 2014 & 2016, 2017, 2020
- ERP SAP System Implementation Finance project lead 2000,2006,2013,2019. IFS 2021 & 2022
- Change Management certification workshops. 20011 & 2014
- Sarbanes Oxley 404. (SOX) and CARM certification 2005 & 2008, 2011,2018
- SAP, IFS, Salesforce & Microsoft Dynamics 2012, 2014 & 2020, Quick Books 2018

Volunteer Experience

- Past Board of Director Member BPO Economic Development Board. 2016-2018.
- Past Board of Director Member National Training Agency Education. 2014-2015

Professional Affiliations

Fellow of the ACCA/CPA. Qualified Member of CIMA, CGMA.